

Ilia Bakhterev

Summary

My primary goal of my mission is to strongly integrate automation and monitoring at all steps of the software and system development. My experience is more than 6 years of engineering, administrating, automating and implementing IaC approaches. I believe that process automation makes software development better. I have strong skills at research, analyzing data, communications.

bakhterets@gmail.com

Education

2009 - 2014

(Russian Federation)

KOSTROMA STATE AGRICULTURAL ACADEMY

Diploma specialist of information technology in the energy sector. Electrification and automation.

Main skills

Configuration Management	Ansible, Ansible Tower, Terraform, Microsoft SCCM, NetBox
Infrastructure	Linux, Windows (DHCP, DNS, Sites and Services, Certificate Services and etc.) VMWare Server Appliance, PostgtreSQL, MariaDB, Nginx, Haproxy, Jira and Confluence (as service owner), GitLab (as service owner), AWX (as service owner)
Virtualization	Hyper-V (VMM), ESXi (vCenter), KVM
Private Clouds	Microsoft Azure Pack and Azure Stack, vCloud Director and vRealize Automation.
Public Clouds	AWS, Yandex, SberCloud
CI/CD and Development	Git (GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket), Subversion, Molecule, CI/CD – GitLab generally, jFrog Artifactory
Programming	Bash, PowerShell, python
Containerization	Docker, Podman, k8s, Helm
Monitoring	Zabbix, Prometheus, Sentry, SCOM, Grafana, Grafana LOKI, Elastic Stack and Open Distro, VictoriaMetrics, Synthetic monitoring scripts (python, bash, PowerShell)

Experience

SENIOR MONITORING ENGINEER (SRE ROLE) "SBERCLOUD" (CLOUD PROVIDER)

May 2021 - Now

Responsibilities:

- Automation of deployment of monitoring systems
- Development of non-standard monitoring solutions
- · Ensuring continuous operation of monitoring systems
- · Integration of monitoring systems with cloud products
- Writing documentation
- · Incident management

Accomplishments

- Improving the automation of interaction between infrastructure systems and monitoring systems
- Development of custom monitoring for VMWare products (Appliance and API vCloud Director)
- Creation of geo-distributed monitoring for external Cloud services

SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR - "DEUTSCHE TELEKOM IT SOLUTIONS"

March 2019 - May 2021

Responsibilities:

- Development of the company's infrastructure architecture
- · Maintenance and deployment of two private clouds
- · Monitoring of the company's infrastructure
- Automation of the processes of the company's infrastructure
- Planning and conducting the purchase of hardware and software for the company's infrastructure

Accomplishments

- Implementation of the IaC approach in the work of the team
- · Migrating customer repositories from SVN to GitLab
- Deployment a private cloud and migrate customer services and systems to a new cloud without downtime (From Azure Pack to vCloud vRealize)
- Project support for the development of a digital signature system for internal company documents as a DevOps engineer and project deployment
- Contributed to DevOps School by T-Systems

SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR - "SVETLANA JSC"

Feb 2016 - March 2019

Responsibilities:

- Support and maintenance company infrastructure
- Software and hardware service
- Ensuring the smooth operation of production information systems
- Infrastructure architecture development

Accomplishments

- Improving the automation of interaction between infrastructure systems and monitoring systems
- Implementation of version control system
- Implementation of monitoring system in infrastructure
- Automation of backup processes

ELECTRICAL DESIGN & PLANNING ENGINEER - "ART ENGINEERING SPB"

Nov 2015 - Feb 2016

Responsibilities:

- Design of electrical systems and communications
- Writing technical documentation

Accomplishments

- Project of electrification of a boiler house for the Hanhikivi Nuclear Power Plant
- Project of electrification of a mobile boiler module for the Yamal LNG